welcome back to another video editing
欢迎回到另一个视频编辑
tutorial using the free software
使用免费软件的教程
kdenlive
克登利夫
in our last video we use this butterfly
在我们的上一个视频中 我们使用了这只蝴蝶
and this image of this coastline to
这张海岸线的图像
create to demonstrate the chroma key
创建以演示色度键
green screen effect we're gonna repeat
我们将重复绿幕效果
that in this one because we're gonna be
这是因为我们将成为
going over animation and showing how to
复习动画并演示如何
actually move this butterfly across the
实际上把这只蝴蝶移过
screen and animate in kdenlive so first
Kdenlive中的屏幕和动画是如此之先
of all we're going to reapply the chroma
最重要的是 我们将重新应用色度
key we find the chroma key under alpha
键我们在Alpha下找到色度键
manipulation we'll just drag it on top
我们只要把它拖到上面就行了
of the butterfly and then we click here
然后我们点击这里
on this little drop and select our color
在这个小水滴上选择我们的颜色
and that will should change everything
这一意愿应该会改变一切
that's when we go in here yeah so that
那就是我们进来的时候 对 所以
changes everything so that we can
改变了一切 这样我们就可以
actually see now the background so now
实际上现在看到了背景所以现在
we can see our background the butterfly
我们可以看到我们的背景是蝴蝶
is kind of flying here we can kind of
就像是在这里飞行 我们可以
scroll through and see what this looks
滚动浏览 看看这是什么样子
like but the butterfly is staying there
就像蝴蝶待在那里一样
and it's not moving and so we might want
它不会移动 所以我们可能想要
to adjust the size of it too or change
也要调整它的大小或更改
some different things so what we can do
一些不同的事情 所以我们可以做的是
let's erase all this go back to our
让我们抹去这一切回到我们的
effects and we'll go to crop and
效果 我们将去裁剪和
transform and then we'll get a transform
变换 然后我们将得到一个变换
so not all effects allow for animation
因此 并不是所有的效果都支持动画
but transform is one that does and if
但转变是这样做的 如果
ever you have you pull in an effect and
你有没有让你产生一种效果
it has this little bar the top with with
它有一个小栏杆 顶部有
a couple triangles you know that you can
几个你知道你可以做到的三角形
perform you can do animation or you can
表演你可以做动画 或者你可以
set keyframes and have that effect
设置关键帧并实现该效果
applied differently at different points
在不同的点上用法不同
of the clip so what we're gonna do we
所以我们接下来要做的是
have these different buttons here right
把这些不同的按钮放在这里
now this triangle if we notice moves
现在这个三角形如果我们注意到它在移动
according to where we're at on our
根据我们在我们的
timeline so if we move our timeline
时间线所以如果我们移动时间线
towards the end of the video this
在视频接近尾声的时候
triangle is towards the end and we can
三角形快到尽头了 我们可以
also move the triangle here on the
同时将三角形移至此处
timeline I mean up here and it'll move
时间线我是说在这里它会移动
the playhead on our timeline so these
我们时间线上的播放头 所以这些
are tied together if we hit this
如果我们击中这个 就会被绑在一起
triangle with the line at the start of
以直线为起点的三角形
it it goes to the first frame of our
如果它转到我们的第一帧
video clip and if we go to the click
视频剪辑 如果我们点击
this it goes to the last frame of our
这是我们节目的最后一帧
video clip and so we notice at the first
视频剪辑 所以我们首先注意到
frame there is if we come here to the
如果我们来到这里 就会有一个框架
middle and look there's a red triangle
中间看有一个红色的三角形
at the start that's our key
一开始 这就是我们的关键
rame so we have a keyframe starting at
所以我们有一个关键帧开始于
the beginning to make this butterfly
开始制造这只蝴蝶
animate or move we need to set at least
动画或移动我们至少需要设置
one more keyframe and a good place to do
再一个关键帧和一个很好的位置
it just for starting is to set it at the
只是为了开始 就是把它设置在
end of the video clip so let's hit this
视频片段的结尾 让我们开始吧
arrow to go to the end of the video clip
指向视频剪辑末尾的箭头
make sure the playhead is at the end of
确保播放头位于
our video and then we'll hit the plus
我们的视频 然后我们会打加号
sign and that adds a keyframe so now I
签名 这添加了一个关键帧 所以现在我
have a red triangle at the end it's kind
最后有一个红色的三角形 很亲切
of hard to see and I have a triangle at
很难看到 我在那里有一个三角形
the beginning so that's how we know we
所以这就是我们如何知道我们
have two keyframes then anything that
有两个关键帧 那么任何
any way that we change this butterfly
不管我们如何改变这只蝴蝶
the size of it or the location of it any
无论它的大小或位置
of these settings that we change below
我们在下面更改的这些设置中
here it will it will transition I guess
我想在这里它会过渡的
you can say between what was happening
你可以说在发生的事情之间
at the first keyframe and what's
在第一个关键帧和什么
happening at the last keyframe so let's
发生在最后一个关键帧 所以让我们
go back to our first keyframe we'll see
回到我们的第一个关键帧 我们将看到
it looks like this okay so it's this
看起来是这样的 好的 就是这样
size maybe we want at our first keyframe
在我们的第一个关键帧可能需要的大小
let's resize it down and let's have the
让我们缩小它的大小 让我们
butterfly be over here towards the left
蝴蝶在这里往左走
a little bit lower about that size and
稍微低一点 大约那个大小
then we see there's a line here so it's
然后我们看到这里有一条线 所以它是
showing us where it's going by the last
最后告诉我们它的去向
keyframe so let's go to the last
关键帧 让我们跳到最后一帧
keyframe and see okay so it's going to
关键帧 并看到好的 所以它将
be this size and it's going to be at
是这个大小 那么它就会是
this position so we can resize that too
这个位置 这样我们也可以调整它的大小
and move it and maybe we want it even
把它移走 也许我们想要扯平
smaller like forward so now it's going
更小 像前进一样 所以现在它正在前进
to be it's going to go from this first
因为它将首先从这个开始
keyframe to this last keyframe over the
关键帧到此最后一个关键帧
duration of it's about only one second
它的持续时间大约只有一秒
is all of our all that our video clip is
我们的视频片段就是我们的全部吗？
so now we can just come and play that
现在我们可以来玩这个游戏了
and see what that will look like so we
看看那会是什么样子 所以我们
go back to the beginning hit play and we
回到开始的热门剧目 我们
see our butterfly is kind of flying
看我们的蝴蝶在飞翔
along that path it happened really short
沿着那条小路 它发生得很短
but I can go drag along and show you so
但我可以拖着走给你看
it's this is just what's happening the
这就是正在发生的事情
butterfly is flying the backgrounds
蝴蝶在背景中飞舞
moving we've created an animated little
令人感动的是 我们创造了一个动画小游戏
butterfly here and we don't have to just
蝴蝶在这里 我们不必只是
do if we go back in click on this track
如果我们返回 请点击此曲目
and go to the effects for the transform
然后转到要变换的效果
as long as we're on our keyframe if
只要我们在我们的关键帧上
we're in the middle look we have we
我们在中间看我们有我们
can't control any of these we can't
我们不能控制任何这些我们不能
change the size or anything
更改大小或其他任何东西
because we're not on a keyframe so you
因为我们不在关键帧上所以你
have to always be on a keyframe so you
必须始终位于关键帧上 这样您就可以
can click on this frame or you can use
可以点击此框 也可以使用
these start and end and if we wanted it
这些开始和结束 如果我们想要它
to do something different we can go to
做一些我们可以去做的不同的事情
the middle and we can add a keyframe in
我们可以在中间添加一个关键帧
the middle and we can have it do
在中间 我们可以做到
something like this like fly it up and
像这样的东西 飞起来 然后
then over and so now if we do that look
然后 现在如果我们这样做的话
what will happen it'll fly it'll go up
会发生什么 它会飞 它会飞起来
and follow this sort of path we've set
沿着我们设定的这条路走
for it and then it'll go over so we've
然后它就会过去 所以我们
created yeah an animation they were
创造了一部动画 他们是
doing that let's go back to the very
这样做 让我们回到最
first keyframe and we can also change
第一个关键帧 我们也可以改变
some different things what do we do we
一些不同的事情 我们该做什么
did scale so one other thing we can
做了扩展 所以我们可以做的另一件事
change is rotation so we can rotate this
改变是旋转 所以我们可以旋转这个
butterfly a little bit as it's flying we
当蝴蝶飞舞的时候 我们
can have it rotate so it starts like
可以让它旋转 这样它开始时就像
this maybe it's gonna fly it with want
这也许会让它带着渴望飞翔
to fly it up we can have it I don't want
飞起来 我们可以拥有它 我不想要
to be too extreme but then that'll
太极端了 但那会
change the rotation and as it's going
改变旋转方向 随着时间的推移
it's gonna rotate around so we can
它会旋转 这样我们就可以
change rotation and scale and different
更改旋转和缩放以及不同
different properties that way so I would
不同的属性 所以我会
recommend you play with this if you
建议你玩这个 如果你
didn't watch the last video go ahead and
我没有看最后一段视频 继续
watch it because I show where to
看吧 因为我会告诉你去哪里
download this green screen butterfly
下载这张绿屏蝴蝶
it's actually a pretty good object for
它实际上是一件很好的物品
learning how to get started in animating
学习如何开始制作动画
in kdenlive what else and then maybe
在Kdenlive还有什么 然后可能
watch some other videos on actually how
观看一些关于实际如何操作的其他视频
keyframing and how video works if you're
关键帧设置以及视频的工作原理
kind of getting confused and it's not
有点困惑 但这并不是
working well just make sure you always
做好工作只是要确保你总是
have to add in this keyframe and you
必须添加此关键帧 然后您
can't add it where an existing keyframe
无法将其添加到现有关键帧所在的位置
is or you won't have any movement what
是不是你不会有任何动作
else okay so you can also change the
否则 好的 所以您还可以更改
opacity which doesn't really help us in
不透明并不能真正帮助我们
this case but if by this keyframe if you
这种情况下 但如果通过此关键帧
want the opacity to be down like at 32%
希望不透明度降到32%
it changes so that this is kind of like
它会改变 所以这就像是
not very bright not very bright it's not
不太亮不太亮不太亮
it's transparent and so now if we do
这是透明的 所以现在如果我们这样做了
that it starts out with full all the
它从所有的一切开始
full colors and then by the time it gets
全彩色 然后当它变得
to that keyframe it's changed to not to
到该关键帧 它已更改为不
like almost see-through and then it
就像几乎是透明的 然后它
becomes light again so we wouldn't want
又变轻了 所以我们不想
to do that in this case but sometimes
在这种情况下这样做 但有时
you want I just want to show you that
你想要我只是想让你看看
opacity is also keyframe Abul so you can
不透明度也是关键帧 因此您可以
have an object fade
使对象淡入淡出
in as part of the animation yeah so
作为动画的一部分 是的 所以
that's it so watch for some of these
就是这样 所以要注意其中一些
other ones have you can keyframe the
其他类型具有您可以设置关键帧的
audio some of these audio things on
打开其中一些音频设备的音频
under audio Corrections there's this
在音频更正下 有以下内容
volume that's keyframe Abul so you can
音量是关键帧ABUL 因此您可以
set a keyframe with your audio too
也用你的音频设置一个关键帧
sometimes so maybe you want to have it
有时候 所以也许你想拥有它
start out kind of soft and then at a
开始的时候有点柔和 然后
certain portion of the video you want to
视频的某些部分您想要
have it be loud again you can use the
让它再大声一点 你可以用
keyframe on audio to do that too so go
音频上的关键帧也可以这样做 所以请继续
ahead and just play with this watch this
继续玩这个游戏 看这个
tutorial over again if you need to and
如果需要 请重新学习教程
follow the steps that I did and just get
按照我做过的步骤去做 然后
familiar doing that because you can undo
熟悉这样做是因为你可以撤销
a lot of cool stuff with animation video
动画视频中有很多很酷的东西
overtop of video we could add in a third
除了视频之外 我们还可以添加三分之一
object and animate it in you can rotate
对象并在其中设置其动画 您可以旋转
and have you can create your own
你有没有能力创建自己的
transitions basically using animation
基本使用动画的过渡
and transparent layers so hopefully you
和透明的层 所以希望你
found this informative go ahead and like
发现这个信息继续前进 喜欢
and subscribe comment below and I'll
并订阅下面的评论 我会
catch you in the next video
在下一个视频中看到你